Melanie Phillips

Web Developer

www.melaniephillips.io

melanie@melaniephillips.io

(905) 719-9926

Twitter: @MountainMel

PROFILE

I'm a bilingual (French/English) Web Developer with 12 years of experience in toy & game manufacturing and distribution. I've been coding for several years, but have upgraded my skills significantly in the past 6 months. I'm a recent graduate of HackerYou's Web Development Immersive.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Everest Toys, Hamilton, ON - *VP Logistics*

SEPT 2016 - DEC 2017

- Built and maintained in-house logistics portal using HTML & CSS
- Oversaw logistical processes for all inbound and outbound products
- Managed all equipment and logistics staff (20-30 employees)

Everest Toys, Hamilton, ON — Senior Product Manager

JAN 2013 - AUG 2016

- Sourced new/popular product lines
- Maintained existing distribution relationships & inventory levels
- Organized manufacturing and testing for in-house product lines

Everest Toys, Hamilton, ON — Bilingual Sales Manager

JULY 2006 - DEC 2012

- Built and maintained the company's first website using HTML & CSS
- Organized and oversaw the company's booth at industry trade shows
- Managed sales team performance & expectations

EDUCATION

HackerYou College of Technology

Toronto, ON - Web Development Certificate

JAN 2018 - MAR 2018

McMaster, Hamilton, ON — English & Cultural Studies

SKILLS & TOOLS

JavaScript

jQuery

React

Git & GitHub

Command Line

Firebase

APIs

Gulp

CSS3/Sass

HTML

Responsive Design

VOLUNTEER WORK

Canada Learning Code -

Workshop Mentor

LANGUAGES

English (First Language)
French (Full Fluency)

INTERESTS

Learning - Currently enjoying IoT devices and data science

Reading - Especially fantasy & sci-fi

Gaming - PC & Steam

Being outdoors - Camping, canoeing, rock climbing and hiking.